## Karina Sanchez

8360 Whippoorwill Dr. Fort Worth, TX 76123 | (682)760-1868 | ksanchez1234@outlook.com

#### **Profile**

Highly experienced professional individual with over 5 years of dedicated experience. Able to work in a fast-paced environment, with minimum supervision, while maintaining emphasis on the highest quality of consumer service and benefit towards my employer. Self-motivated, hardworking and resourceful individual, decision making and excellent critical thinking, problem solving, interpersonal and bi-lingual communication skills.

#### Education

### BS in Computer Science with a concentration in Software Engineering

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, NH

Anticipated Graduation Date June 2021

#### Certificate in Web Development

Shaw Academy, Online

Anticipated Graduation Date August 2021

### **Information Communication Technology Basics**

University of Texas at Arlington, Arlington, TX

May 2018

### **Basic Core Competencies**

Java Script | GitHub | SQL Database | HTML | CSS | Excel | JQuery | PHP | Microsoft Office | React | Redux | Python

## **Computer Science Projects**

**Prototype Android Mobile App**: Designed and developed a mobile Android application using Java and Android Studio. Selected appropriate framework and approach as well as designed human-computer interfaces based on requirements and targeted audience.

**MongoDB RESTful API**: Developed a web service using software stack and implemented an industry standard interface. Made use of MongoDB API service to enable application as specialized information storage and retrieval service.

**Secure Code Audit Report**: Analyzed source code through manual and automated testing methods for vulnerabilities and code weaknesses. Recommended testing processes and protocols necessary for securing program designs/architectures.

**Prototype Weather Condition Embedded System Device:** Created and extended capability of weather station prototype. Built a custom software component that controlled the sensors and the sending, receiving, and storing of data using JSON files and embedded system devices like Raspberry Pi and Grove Pi.

#### Other Professional Experience

Business Analyst PennyMac Loan Services, Fort Worth, TX

Feb. 2021 - Current

- Promoted from Cash Management on February 16th, 2021
- Assisted frontend, backend, and design team developers with user guides, wrote user stories, set up meetings, and assisted with blocked issues.
- Helped with the development and creation of applications and created UAT for testing.
- Currently being cross trained as a developer in React and Redux for the next features being updated to system.

# Processor I Cash Management, PennyMac Loan Services, Fort Worth, TX

April 2018 - Feb. 2021

- Promoted from Customer Service on April 4th, 2018
- Monitor activities and workflow to ensure goals and objectives of the department are met
- Delegate work to associates to ensure payments are posted timely and that general ledgers are reconciled
- Resolves problems and customer complaints through research and reconstruction of loan payment history
- Used Excel and SQL database to gather data and prepare various reports for QC team.

#### Customer Service, PennyMac Loan Services, Fort Worth, TX

Nov. 2016 – April 2018

- Addressed customer concerns and issues regarding mortgage escrow, ACH accounts, PMI, payoffs, and payments.
- Assisted customers on accessing the PennyMac website.
- Follow ups, assisted with forbearance plans, sent requested documents to customers and answered secure messages.

### Immigration Consultant, USCIS, Fort Worth, TX

May 2016-September 2016

- Met customer needs and provided the right solution to their immigration problems
- Created service request, checked processing times, reviewed case numbers and their status

Sales and Marketing Representative, Just Energy, Irving, TX Passenger Service Agent, World Flight Service, Dallas, TX Airport Dispatcher, Gate Service, Dallas, TX Customer Service Representative, Sam's Club, El Paso, TX

March 2016-May 2016 September 2015-January 2016 July 2015-September 2015 December 2014-May 2015